It's 6:00, so we're going to go ahead
and get started. Um,
roll call. Uh, Mill, oh wait.
Sorry.
Um, Gary has excused himself, so we know
he's going to be absent. David?
>> Here.
>> And
Don is also Josh.
>> Here.
>> Elizabeth?
It did not work. Here.
Uh, Patrick Bustos?
>> Here.
>> Kelly?
>> Jack?
>> Here.
>> Patrick uh uh
Don is excused as well.
Um
Um, I guess uh does someone want to make
a motion to approve or have any comments
on the
minutes
from the February meeting?
>> I would move to approve the minutes.
>> Anyone a second?
>> Second.
>> Okay. Uh, comments?
I have just one. Um
my name is spelled incorrectly.
Um
under roll call, this is Amber Cromwell.
Just a little bit of correction there.
Well, but up here it says Cromwell.
That's okay.
Okay.
Uh all any other comments?
All in favor?
>> I.
>> All right.
Okay.
So, does anyone have any disclosures,
conflicts of interest?
No.
Do we have any audience online?
I guess comments report from
City Council.
>> I'll be already. Okay.
Uh well, first off, sorry I wasn't here
for our meeting last month. Uh
we had an event where the PRCA
uh came and gave a presentation to
uh the legislature
and the
City Council leaders and uh CFD.
And then last night we passed a
resolution
uh
saying that we're going to support
the ProRodeo
uh
headquarters being moved to Cheyenne and
the Hall of Fame.
And that's about a $60 million deal. So,
we're going to have a
a hitching post district on the corner,
the southwest corner of I-25 and I-80.
And uh that's where that will be and
pretty much all of it will be
uh
related to our western culture.
Uh
the other big news was we signed a
a
service agreement with
to finish the design on the pump house.
And
according to
Jason Sanchez, they're going to probably
start reconstruction on that this fall.
>> That's awesome.
>> Yeah, so
maybe we'll have a ribbon cutting in a
little over a year. Uh
that that's really exciting.
Uh
And then
we heard from the Wyoming Business
Council
and it was called Leading Economic
Growth, Building Resilient Communities,
and Creating Opportunities. And
it was I found a couple things that were
interesting where it was
separating myth from reality.
The first one was that Wyoming's economy
is doing just fine. Well,
uh the reality is we're in a long-term
decline.
Uh the second one was
that I found interesting.
That uh
the boomerang effect where a lot of the
young people that leave Wyoming for
careers or for college will eventually
come back.
Uh that is very small.
And
the third one was
uh that Wyoming people don't want
Wyoming to grow. And uh the reality is
most Wyomingites
do support
uh growth.
But you wouldn't have been able to tell
it by our meeting last night.
>> Sorry.
>> I'm leaving.
>> Uh for about 3 hours we
discussed the annexation, which was
mostly
uh controversial with
uh WyFresh Farm.
And ultimately we decided to move third
reading to November 9th.
Just to give them
more time to feel comfortable with
going from county to city. I think one
of the
things that we didn't really talk a lot
about was the county's unwillingness to
uh
come
let them know about any violations that
they had with the county codes. They
were just kind of letting them do
whatever they wanted to do.
Isn't that kind of how you saw it,
Charles?
>> That's exactly how it is.
>> Yeah, and you know, that's how they want
to keep it. Well,
uh hopefully over the next 8 months the
county will
you know,
let them know about some of the things
that they need to straighten out over
there.
Uh
and really not a lot more on the agenda.
We did repeal the storm water fee.
Uh that was also
kind of a backroom deal with the
legislature. They decided to kill the
bills that they were
sponsoring
uh that would have required that to go
to a vote
and uh
go to the people.
And we compromised they're sending that
to an interim
study with the select water committee.
And uh they have three accounts at the
legislature.
Uh
I just call them water one, water two,
water three. But the first one is for
uh small water projects around the
state.
Uh the second one is for reclamation
projects.
And the third one are for larger
projects like dams and reservoirs.
Uh
there's probably not enough money in the
all three of those accounts put together
to take care of the storm water fee
statewide and there's
a couple of communities that have been
doing storm water collections for
decades.
So,
Cheyenne and Laramie were the two that
were uh
causing
this little rift between the legislature
and and the communities, but it was the
legislature 2020 that actually
uh passed some legislation that
authorized
us to do what we did.
And then they didn't like us doing what
they told us to do, so they undid it.
Shh, doesn't make a lot of sense, but
that's kind of legislature giveth and
the legislature taketh away.
Uh the other one
was
out at the Goanas Park,
we have a bid now uh
with DUSTECH Construction to create a
trail system
that's going to go over there by where
the water
is for where the
the bird habitat is. They're going to
have a
set up some bird blinds for people to go
over there and and watch.
And I can't remember what Genie said,
Genie Shrednik, when she was saying that
they identified over 50 different
species of birds
that uh
uh or water fowl that nest over there.
So, uh
one of the problems we're having is a
lot of people like to take their dogs
out there and just let them run loose.
So,
there will be signs there that uh dogs
need to be on leash
and hopefully community will
uh
follow the law.
And that's all I got and I do have
another personal commitment tonight, so
I'm
going to go ahead and take off, too.
>> Got it. I just have one question on and
maybe
Charles and Aaron will have a better
answer, but I haven't looked at for the
urban farm, do we have a zoning in the
city that covers urban farm?
>> They ain't one.
>> Urban what? No.
>> Well, that's what I just kind of keep
seeing, so I didn't know if
>> The quick one-on-one on
on the farm,
um, is we
have an agricultural an agricultural
zone district and a agricultural
residential zone district. In those two
zone districts, they allow limited
agricultural operations. The ag zone
district allows agricultural
um, operations.
Now, in our development code, we don't
have very many specific uses. Uses are
purposefully, um, identified very
broadly. For example, you might see one
that says
personal services and that can represent
anything from a
a nail salon to a massage, uh, studio to
wellness studio. We take that and we
group it into the personal service where
it could be permitted in the zone
district.
Um, for the
operations that were occurring at Y
Fresh Farms, um, it's our opinion that
it really fell into two of the existing
land uses, which it doesn't really
matter because they're both permitted
uses. It's general agriculture and
limited agriculture.
Um, out of a courtesy to them at the
beginning, we said, "Well, we understand
that you're calling yourself an urban
farm."
And we're like, well, we can make an
interpretation that sure, urban farm can
be a
a land use, and we'll put together this
policy document, which is on our
website, shancity.org/udc.
You can see it on there.
Where the urban farm falls in the same
classifications as general agriculture
and limited agriculture. So, the purpose
was just to say, yep, we recognize that
even though you call it an urban farm,
it's a permitted use.
So, the direction now is for us to make
it appears where we're trying to figure
out the exact direction.
Um but we've identified 12 ordinances
that we need to pass
to
address
the
comments received.
Everything from changing our code to
allow electric fences for agricultural
use, not an issue.
To changing our code to allow people to
shoot guns with protection of animals in
the city. To allow people to have
agricultural exemptions from building
permits. To remove the license
contractor requirement for agricultural
buildings. It really is a whole bunch.
So, we just need to see where the flavor
is right now
with the governing body. Is it to do
exactly what the Nicely's want?
Or is it to
um pave the path forward for the urban
farm.
So, it's about 12 ordinances. We have a
lot of them kind of started. We already
know the path forward, and our staff's
going to put it all together.
Urban farm will probably make it into a
definitions.
You'll probably have some development
standards because
the urban farm, it's a latecomer
to a area surrounded by housing.
The
any new urban farm that's established
is going to be adjacent to another land
use very likely.
Um and we still need to have
considerations that
they're not producing nuisances such as
excessive flies and smells and and noise
and stuff because the neighbors that
were there first still have that
expectation.
Um, there's been a real different, um,
picture painted on
that particular farming use, but we're
just trying to make it comfortable so
they have an avenue to expand forward.
But, we're not willing to give them
permission to build unsafe structures,
structures that don't meet the deal J
standards for ADA, um, or permission to
have a
no, um,
no restrictions on development that
can't injure the neighboring properties.
That's the delicate balance that we're
looking for.
So, long story short, yes, urban farm
is undefined in the unified development
code, but it's covered under two other
definitions.
Actually, I think it's three the way the
interpretation goes.
>> Okay. I'm just curious.
>> We've been putting a lot of time on
this. Uh,
we met with them yesterday for 2 and 1/2
hours with the mayor and six of our
directors.
Uh, they submitted 147 questions.
Um,
I think they they had even worked
through the weekend to try and get these
all answered for them. And, uh,
we've really bent over backwards to try
and accommodate.
And yet,
I think
public perception on social media is
that we're trying to take their farm.
Nobody on city council
That's That's not what we're
trying to do. We want them to be
successful.
Just like we do with the thousand other
businesses in in town.
But yet, this one
s- needs, uh,
little more attention.
So,
>> Understood.
>> Anyway,
that's about all I got to
We'll see where we go.
>> Um
Just a quick
question about the pump house.
I know there's
um
plans to do some work there. Um and I
don't know if this is a question for you
uh Ken or you Charles.
Are there any stipulations in the work
or should we be concerned about um in
integrity,
res- preserving the character,
preserving, you know,
historic materials there at all? Um is
I'm just curious is that
been
broached at all or is that something we
need to be concerned about or is that
um is that particular place is not on
the national register and so I
I'm just curious if that's something we
should be
concerned about or not concerned about
or just
you the city's going to do what the
city's going to do?
>> I Well, I guess I'll kind of sort of let
you guys answer after, but um I know
that TDSI um has
tried to get that preserved for decades
now. And so I wouldn't imagine that they
would do anything that would
harm the integrity of the building.
Um
I mean, they even found the original
roof material that that's readily
available to go back on there. That
being said, budget matters and you do
kind of question if things all kind of
get changed a little bit. Um but I guess
they I mean,
do they have to come to us if it's not
on the register or
>> And to answer three, the members of the
of the board, no, if it's not on the
register or listed as a contributing
structure, they don't have to go to you
all. However, um as the plans are
developed,
they'll be developed, they'll be
available for public inspection. We'll
do our best to make sure they do go to
the board for review at different
levels.
Um, just as a cursory review. Um, but
any contract to actually award the
construction project is a public
process,
um, where it would go to our finance
committee, um, after referral into the
governing body, where the exact same
conversation
that occurred last time could occur.
Just with much more heavy fiscal
consequences at 100% design plans.
So, it'd be in the benefit of everyone
to
have you all included in that review
process, and I don't envision it not
happening because we do
we do communicate with them, and we can
send that message.
>> I have a quick
>> Oh, sorry. Go ahead.
>> I heard a couple things there.
I just want to look clarification. So,
Charles, are you recommending that we do
this board be part of that process or
just have some input into it? Um, do we
write a letter? Do we ask or do we just
show up for public comment? I
>> Sure, through that board member Bustos,
so what I'm recommending is that our
project manager uh, make sure they
include
either certain people from the um,
historic preservation board or just they
provide the opportunity to comment on
major milestones of project development.
Don't we have a subcommittee kind of
already established for the pump house
right now? That was done a few I would
advise that we would reach out to those
people directly.
Um, so they would be able to provide
comments.
>> Josh.
>> Thank you. Um, yeah, I think Patrick had
great comments cuz it'd be it would be a
bummer to uh,
go through all that and save the
building but lose some of those um,
parts of the historic integrity of the
building. Um, a different topic, a quick
question for
Councilman Esquibel.
You mentioned the
um
the place where the Pro Rodeo
museum is going to go in and you
described it as
a district that's going to be all about
the western heritage. Is there talk of
other organizations moving into that
area or
the way the way you described it as a
district made me
>> Yeah, we heard Cheyenne believes that
they're going to
be putting out
uh
their feelers for
you know, like Stetson hats
Tony Lama boots, places like that that
uh
might have
like a retail
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah, okay.
>> Or maybe even one of their
factories here, something like that.
But, they do want to keep the western
theme in that Hitching Post District.
>> Thank you.
>> Madam Chair, that's all I have.
>> Okay.
And you said you had to leave
for Okay.
Well, thank you for coming and
for writing the report.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, uh
comments report from Planning and
Development.
>> Members of the board, you have seen the
concept design for the Hitching Post
District, correct? Or have you not?
The way it is shown right now is that it
is basically an extension of Clear Creek
Parkway northwesterly.
That curve next to McDonald's where it
would go northbound and it would create
a essentially a large oval
area where you would have different lots
that could be
developed to be more entertainment
based. Um more touristy. It's not
supposed to be data centers or
or anything like the Overland Edition
south of the Flying J. It's supposed to
be tourism and hospitality.
Um so they have the PRC headquarters
which will have the office building.
They're planning on doing the museum and
that'll be kind of tucked uh
on the north
um
eastern portion of that lot. It'll be
visible from I-25 and I-80 cuz it'll be
immediately on the southwest quadrant
there. Um but none of this area this
development would extend north of the
Union Pacific rail line.
So that's kind of where it's located.
You come off where Aaron's has the
mouse.
Uh do a loop. The northwesterly area or
northeasterly area is where the facility
would be.
Um they're really looking to try to find
uses that would complement it.
Um jokingly and maybe it could come to
fruition. I I have joked around that we
should look at relocating the Cascadia
project from Greeley out here since it
failed and we could have a
you know, an NHL affiliate hockey team
come with it. So but that's just a a
dream but
if you don't know about the Cascadia
project, just Google and you'll see what
uh referendum vote did um to community
that bonded 115 million dollars secured
by 46 of their buildings. Now the
project's delayed by
a while. Oops.
And work was already started.
So anyway, um yeah, it's supposed to be
a little tourism district um out there.
Um it's moving fast.
Oh, another updates. Okay, so
I we've had a lot of work on
I working with the
urban farm stuff the final county pocket
annexation. Uh that kind of came up as a
surprise the
um public response to it.
That it does teach us a lot of lessons
in the
planning and development in the
municipal world. Um as we need to make
sure we get ahead of
uh providing the narrative first.
Uh we missed the opportunity and the
narrative kind of ran its own direction
to a point of no recovery.
Um it was
noted early on, but we just are really
thin staffed city wide that's hard to
pivot and react immediately to different
things.
Um in our department we're continuing to
see
um a lot of
new development that's popping in. It's
of all different sizes um from small
accessory buildings all the way to these
large data centers.
Uh we've had
an annexation application come in last
um
last month for 1,000 acres off of Happy
Jack west of
um that
What's that neighborhood?
Whatever the neighborhood is west of the
base.
Um there's a still large undeveloped
land out in between, but there's a large
annexation that's been proposed out that
direction of near the Bapu water
treatment.
Near Yeah, close to Rolling Hills
Estates.
Um we're seeing a lot of uh data center
uh pressure and development that's
coming in at paces that we haven't even
seen yet. Like we're talking
uh
100 to 1,000 thousands of acre business
parks that are looking to be
um coming into the community and
annexing within the next
at least filing with the next 4 months
or so.
Um so we're seeing a lot of potential
revenue.
Um it
with the data centers, you know, we have
uh number one, you're getting additional
property tax assessment and which is
coming into the city's general fund and
benefits the city, the county, um any
other
agency that's receiving property tax.
Um we're seeing a lot of pressure on
housing in the community, and there's a
lot of um
folks um experimenting and seeking to
construct
uh temporary housing of sorts, which
we've identified pass forward um through
the governing body if
people want to develop these large
temporary housing facilities that could
house lots of employees um that could be
bused to and from their destination.
All of this data center construction
continues to move forward. Like, for
example, the Meta data center, I believe
their peak construction estimates was
about 857 employees on site.
That's a lot of heads to put in beds.
Um you have other larger projects like
the related one out um on Venture Drive,
which will easily hit that number.
Uh the Gold Mine west of town is about
to kick off.
Uh they're looking to come in with a
um larger parking area for their
employees so they don't have to drive
all the way up to the Gold Mine site,
which is out by the Herriman mines,
where they would bus them back and
forth.
We're seeing a lot of a lot of uh
pressure on uh data centers and housing.
Um we're seeing
additional um development come through
with
uh the what I think is some of the most
boring architecture ever with fast food
restaurants. They seem to have lost all
their flavor, and they're almost just
like a big black box. Like, really?
Where is the flavor here? So, just burn
burn the buns, whatever. I don't care.
So, seeing um
a lot of that. We're still
um working with uh developers on uh
multi-family housing.
Uh we have a new uh residential
development that's popped up on Powder
House Road. Um just recently got an
approval for planning annexation
with the city's annexation in the
section section 20 Cole family land. Um,
but also a rezone of multi-family and
it's for a 56 unit um
cooperative
housing environment where basically
everyone owns their own unit, but their
building is maintained similar to a
condo
um organization. It's really a a
corporation. It kind of mirrors like
single-family
home ownership because they own that.
Um, it's definitely a unique a unique
item in our city that's just uh
north of the retirement facility near
Melton and Powerhouse just north of
Prairie Avenue off that direction.
>> That's what I was going to ask on
Powerhouse. There's also a retirement or
a or is it a life care center that's
going in between like the existing one
and Coyote Ridge?
>> That's this that's not a retirement
facility, but that's that's the it's age
restricted, but it is the cooperative
It's called the Village Cooperative.
It'll be like a four-story building a
three-story building with a parking in
the
lower-level basement. They have an
indoor car wash for the residents and
active storage lockers for their bikes
and stuff like that. It's it's really an
interesting concept that um is kind of
new.
Um, we do have a lot of single-family
housing that's being constructed out um
or being planned to be constructed in
near Anderson Elementary on Converse and
Story.
Uh, that development out there
um is one of our
newer developments where they really
went with small lots to try to bring
down affordability and such.
Um, other things we're working on is
we'll be working on closing out our
brownfield revolving loan fund
uh grant with the
the feds. Um, it's
we haven't really been able to to a lot
of time and energy into keeping that
going. Um and the grant can also close
this month. Honestly, it would be nice
to be done because I had a lot of a lot
of work and we just don't have the
bandwidth to to manage that. Um doesn't
mean the resource for the Brownfield
Revolving Loan Fund for like
low-interest loans and grants for
nonprofits is gone.
Uh the state has a revolving loan fund
that also needs to be used, so we can
tap into that. And it might be better
for us to work in partnership with the
state, let them manage it, and then we
can um help everyone to keep those loans
active.
A couple a few month about a month ago,
we submitted a grant application to the
EPA for a half million-dollar EPA
assessment grant.
Um you all might um be impressed with
this assessment grant
uh because one of the components of it
is to
look at adaptive reuse of a couple of
the schools that are proposed for
closure under the Mercer
um study. That's the study that
evaluated our our schools and such. Um
and what we needed for our students. Um
one of the schools up for closing is
Hebard Elementary, which is located on
the south side.
That is also in a recognized historic
district, which is the Laramie County uh
schools historic district, where it's a
kind of a patchwork uh
historic district.
Um at first they had indicated the
district that they were going to sell it
and or demo it. They really didn't want
that, but then I had a conversation with
them about its importance, and they
said, "Oh."
And then I gave them a probability of
the demolition, and they said, "Oh."
Um so they're going to put on that this
assessment grant, if we get it awarded,
um it won't really become active until
like November of 2027,
October 2027 actually, I believe.
Um but it allows for
um planning activities, including
adaptive reuse, structural analysis, and
those types of items with that building,
um as well as identifying um potential
contaminants that could be there.
So, it's pretty exciting. Um it's one
that we set to to really look at trying
to preserve some of that the history out
there.
Regarding other stuff in our department,
um
we're still here. We're all here still.
Um I first time I did a presentation
Well, I did a presentation today at the
Mayor's Youth Council.
And for the first time, I didn't have to
change
any of our staff members' names, which
was straight out shocking.
So, that was pretty cool.
Um
and what else do we have going on? I
think Do you have anything to add?
Yeah, we're just busy, lots of different
things. Um
Yeah, the legislature is coming to a
close. Um most of the
biggest bill that the city was watching
was the
um stormwater,
which was
did not pass, but was referred to an
interim committee.
Um that fast-track permits bill, which
doesn't affect the city because we're
fast enough with our reviews, um that
one was approved.
Um I don't know if the
exactions and impact fee once was
approved though. I'd have to
double-check that, but most everything
we're watching died, which was pretty
good.
Um the city did get additional money
through the direct distribution.
Um I understand that right now when you
have the four pennies, the city would
get
30% of the four pennies.
Now, it's moved up to 38%, so it's a
good chunk of change.
And there were no
changes to taxes on electricity or
removal of property tax tax.
Or there weren't too many changes for
voting, either.
But they tried.
So,
that's what I have for now.
Oh, and where and
and the contract payment for the current
uh stuff, everything
should be good to go. Invoices were
supposed to be uploaded on Friday and
then Monday, but our office manager is
sick, so we have a scheduled time for
tomorrow to do that. We actually created
um and working with Reno Renee um Bouvet
with the
Historic Preservation Board, I created
and with Aaron and everyone, uh we
created a SOP that outlines the entire
process from beginning to end from the
CLG all the way down to payment to the
consultants
um or completion of a grant.
Um that was put together and Renee
really really likes it and now wants it
to be a template for the whole state.
So, but we finally were able to sit down
and and get that
after going completely a whole different
direction with our finance department
for months till we're like, "What in the
world happened here?"
So, it's all good.
>> So sorry. Does that mean that oh, it's
coming and everything?
>> will be there. It's going to be in the
pipeline officially on Wednesday,
tomorrow.
It was supposed to be in the pipeline on
Friday.
Um but then uh all hell broke loose for
some reason on Friday and then it ended
up No, I was out on It was supposed to
be Thursday. I was out on Friday.
Um and then Monday it was supposed to be
done and then
that's when we had the illness that kind
of took over.
So, tomorrow morning I think it's like
11 or 10.
1:00, yeah.
So, and a fun fact is we're doing a
city-wide cornhole tournament and we
have a couple of different teams that
are set up. Um you know, beer's allowed
to be held while you're playing
cornhole, kind of makes it weird. Um but
it's cool.
But we have some teams that are playing
in the development department and right
now all of our teams are undefeated and
have advanced to the second round.
>> With no beer. All right.
>> No beer.
>> Well, that is a good
>> Never mind. We're at 500. So, I think
Connor got smoked.
But, Morgan back there, she's going to
the second round.
Our Parks and Greenway persons teamed up
with me and we go live at 9:00 tomorrow.
It'll be on ESPN the Ocho
live.
>> Do you all have any questions for
Charles and Aaron?
Nope.
Okay, so strategic goals report,
National Register of Historic Places.
>> Well, I mean, it sounds like
Charles has got the payments finally
moving forward. So,
Elizabeth, I would just say keep uh
letting us know if you're if you don't
receive them even after this, but um I
don't know if you have any updates on on
the two projects you'd like to give.
>> Yeah, I have a couple. Am I talking into
this tonight? Hello? Okay.
Um so, for the airport terminal, still
doing continued research on that, of
course. Um did give a update for the
Arts and Aviation Committee. That was um
talked or presented to their board, I
believe. Um so, that's nice to see that
going. Um the biggest movement this last
month, though, was on the African
American Context Study. Um I wrote an
article for the Alliance for Historic
Wyoming um on Black History, the
Searchlight Club here in Cheyenne um
which is the oldest um African American
women's social club um in Cheyenne, over
80 years were they functioning. So, um
but through that research, I got some
fantastic leads on um
very, very active community members, not
just in Cheyenne, but all of Wyoming,
um and was able to dig into them and
find some really great census records
and addresses. And there are a few
houses that are still standing. Their
integrity is not fantastic,
unfortunately, but that's just on Google
Earth, so I'll cross my fingers
and hope in person that that's
different. Um so that's that's um the
big excitement, I think, for this month
uh is moving forward on that one. So
that was that was really exciting to
see. Or ex-
check out, research, find out. Yeah.
I
I did have one other um just note on the
nomination for the terminal. Um I did
have the VFLA reach out to me. I don't I
I think you guys sent him my way for
some questions, and they are looking uh
per the grant um that was given to
replace the canopy, they're looking at
um
uh
that construction starting in the next 3
months, um and I he reached out to me
technically because it's not on the
register now, they don't have to come to
us to to do any of this work, um because
it's not in our purview yet, but what I
did say is that we would, if they could
be kind enough to let us know what's
happening and and what those plans are,
because it might hurt us getting it on
the register if they do anything drastic
to change the canopy. Um so he it
sounded like he would give an update
once they kind of have their plans
further developed, but it doesn't sound
like they're going to change anything.
They're the existing canopy is just
to put,
and so it does have to come off, but
they will replace it with in-kind um
material, and it'll look as as it did,
is how he described it. So um but I I
did tell him that until we actually have
the nomination, technically doesn't have
to go through us, but please be kind and
let us know.
>> Maybe this isn't Maybe this isn't the
right place, but I I'm still thinking of
the pump house.
Um
and in terms of
nomination to the National Register, is
that a poss- That's not a possibility in
in the
>> going to pursue that at this time.
They've They've dropped that from the
contract. I saw that that was removed
when they when they passed the current
fees. So, I I don't think they have any
>> intentions.
>> Yeah, I don't think there's any
intention to to do that because it's
still a city property. So, I mean
Yeah, it it would be nice for it to be
recognized, but they don't get any tax
credits or anything like that by putting
it on the register. Um
Right, Charles? Am I crazy?
>> I'm sure, absolutely not.
No.
>> The answer is that's correct. There's no
tax benefit for it. Um if anything, we
could actually record our own facade um
agreement or easement or a covenant on
the building if we really wanted to to
preserve it when all said and done.
Um and
but as long as we retain ownership, um
the threat of the demolition wouldn't
Well,
shouldn't be there. Sorry.
Demo by neglect.
>> Hey, uh anything else for National
Register of Historic Places?
All right, oral histories?
>> Um I don't have any updates on this
since the uh strategic um planning
meeting, other than that it's still
going to be an ongoing effort.
>> All right, historic preservation month.
>> Yep. Well, if we're going to get the
uh the, me, the the Le Clerc Jones award
out by May.
We're going to have to decide on the
nominations tonight,
vote on it in April cuz the next meeting
isn't till April 14th. So, with a month
required to get the the plaque, we're
already to the middle of May
if we want to do it during historic
preservation month.
So, if we
can put a list together and then email
it to everybody that the people that
aren't here and whatever, so that
everybody can visit the sites and see
which ones they want to
vote for.
We need to
put the list together now, I guess.
Okay, we kind of had a somewhat of a
list at the
planning meeting.
>> Um
Yeah, I don't have that on me at the
moment.
Um
I don't
>> So, I was I was at the Albany and then
some other people brought a few other
suggestions up.
>> It's the Albany, um
Why can't I think of the
>> I had mentioned the
Audio Nova. He
was at 20th and Warren.
And
there was one other one I can't reme-
There was one other one I can't remember
what it was.
>> We talked about the Alexis Drake
building.
>> And we've also as a board for the
last year talked on and off about that
the the horse barn.
Um on I think it's on Randall.
>> Yeah, we'll just need a list with the
address then, so those of us who don't
know what the horse barn is.
>> Yeah, it it's been
>> Like so we can email that list out here
this, you know, get the addresses out
and get it cuz uh Gary not being here,
he'll need to
get that uh what soon as he can and uh
and
but like I said, if we want to do that
in uh
award that in May.
The other thing would be the uh Dubois
Award. Do we want to ask the community
for nominations as part of historic
preservation month?
Give them 30 to 60 days cuz if we want
to
give that in like September or October.
You know, cuz usually the list that
comes in we have to kind of vet it cuz
like the last time we did it uh
two of the three nominations already had
uh one of the other of the awards.
And uh you know, if something's
definitely not
historically
you know, you know, that that somebody's
just
nominating it because somebody lived
there that was famous, you know, we have
to
narrow that list down so
uh that's kind of up for discussion if
we want to do do that in May.
Basically just send out a public no uh
what do they call it? Public service
announcement saying we're taking
nominations from the public.
>> I did Oh, go ahead.
>> And then uh
make a uh reference to our website that
shows the list of
the the criteria and the uh list of a
previous winners.
>> I did see on our website that we still
had the link to
um
do the application, but it looks like it
it's no longer active cuz obviously it
was for last year, but I don't know how
easy it is to reactivate that and then
we could put it on our social media,
"Hey, go to
the website and submit an application."
Um cuz I tried to click on it. I can't
remember what the
um application what uh whatever had the
application form. Yeah. Yeah, I think
it's been taken down. It was Matt Murphy
was
in in charge of it
for whatever reason.
So, I can ask him to
redo it for this year.
>> Okay.
>> Cuz I think that'll give us something
else to do for historic preservation
month. It'll get the community
involved in it.
Chair.
>> Okay.
>> Um yeah, David, I think that
um
that's a good idea of the DuBois Award
using the nomination process as a
historic preservation month activity um
because we're already sort of, you know,
behind the timeline for
to do much else, but I think that if
there there would still be time for that
committee, the historic preservation
month committee, to um promote
nominations for the DuBois Award during
historic preservation month. I think
that is a good idea, David. Um
and then the second part, I guess, with
the LeClercq-Jones Award,
I feel like I'm a little confused on the
process that
we're recommending for that. So, you're
putting together this list and then
>> Yeah. Yeah, historically we
everybody everybody on the board gets to
vote, you know,
uh since we're not having the
public uh
sending nominations, we don't our the
the uh
present the committee for the month uh
uh thing won't have to meet.
But, basically everybody's going to
vote, so you need really need to look at
all the nominations to decide which ones
you which one you want to support.
>> Okay.
Um well, it you like I could put that
email together and then um email you to
send out to everyone and
then that way we can come back in April,
we can
vote.
>> I
I wonder if it would be possible to
cuz I I know that in the past like
somebody has gone out and visited the
site and like brought back to us a
recommendation and like whether whether
it is indeed like you know it would be a
good fit or something. And so I wonder
if we could also
sort of like assign
um board members to like go take a
little bit of a closer look or
something.
>> Yeah, you will
>> just because I don't it'll be difficult
to you know come vote on something when
we don't not everybody has
you know seen pictures or been inside of
it or something. I mean I think like
Patrick could go back to the um hearing
center that he's interested in and maybe
see if you could like take bring a
couple pictures back for us or something
like that just so that way next month
when we get here we have something
>> Well
>> to base the conversation on.
>> we need probably buy-in from the owner
too. I don't know if we can just say,
"Hey, we want to give you this award."
and then go, "Well, we're not
interested." I mean that'd be kind of
awkward.
>> It it is.
be to go ahead we will we will have to
contact the owners cuz
I don't know so
sometimes the buildings are leased to
the people that are in the building and
they
the owner itself could be a shell
company out of California
that uh
you may not be even be able to figure
out who the
the real owner is. I don't know the
Secretary of State uh
they they used to be pretty good on
getting you to the actual
president of the company but I don't
know how what they're the new Secretary
of State how whether he's going to be
helpful or not.
Cuz
>> Um
to build on what Josh said I um
last year we actually had a process
where people filled out the application
form.
And I sure would hate to see us
not at least fill out the application
form even if it's one of us um you know
uh
go and visit and collect some
information and get a sign-off on
some representative of the building.
Um, just I think just to keep ourselves
above board and and, you know, um
stick to at least a process that we've
set up and we have a uh a
at least a uh a precedent of doing that
and and
I'd be willing to do that for the one
I'm interested. I don't know about the
others and I don't know anybody at the
Albany and
uh I don't know where the horse barn is
either.
>> I I can contact Alexis straight.
>> Yeah.
>> But I would recommend you actually go
everybody go to the building rather than
uh
rely on just pictures and stuff uh you
know, cuz we don't have enough time to
mess around here. We got a
you got about 4 weeks to get all this
done.
>> Sure.
>> I I don't know that I'll have time to go
to each building, but um I would trust
that whoever
uh of my colleagues on the board would
go and, you know, whoever is going to
the the horse barn could speak to us
about why they think that's appropriate
and
and then we'll take a vote that way.
>> I think the issue with the horse barn
and why we didn't award it is we had
trouble contacting the owner. I don't
think Milward was ever successful in
contacting them.
>> Yeah.
>> I think the general
>> Right.
>> path that process that
>> Patrick is describing, I think,
um makes a lot of sense to me that we
should have one representative from the
board go, maybe with the
with that um form,
try to get that information and then
come back and sort of present it to the
rest of the board.
>> And then we can all
take a look at the same information and
and then cast a vote and off we go.
>> Agreed.
Well, I again, I'm I'm happy to look at
the Alexis Drake building um since I
when they were doing the facade
improvement before I had some contact
with them. Um I'm not really familiar
with the other two. Um
and I I
I don't know if I could really take on
trying to figure out three buildings,
so.
>> Yeah,
yeah, Don and Milward and I went to the
Albany last year
and uh
we and then we tried to find out
that uh was a Blacktooth Brewing, which
turns out that has three different
people leasing that building and we
never did get the
to who actually
Yeah, see see actually the building
owner would have to be the one that
accepts the award. Uh
So,
and then I don't know how the leases are
set up in there for uh
who's responsible for all the uh the
actual building maintenance. I'm
assuming the owner has somebody do that,
but but it just kind of
that's why we didn't do a an award last
year is because we just ran out of time
on trying to do some of that.
>> So, we have
two, right?
You're doing one, Amber?
>> Yes, I I'll look into Alexis Drake.
>> And I'll look into
uh Audio Nova Nova Audio, whatever it
is.
>> with the uh
Albany owner.
>> Okay.
>> I'm pretty sure that they're
you know, it's it changed hands. The
Calluses don't own it anymore, but I'm
pretty sure it's a local
person bought uh the business from them
in the building.
>> Okay, so that that gives us three. Horse
Barn. I if there's no takers, I'll just
>> I have the Albany contact information.
He's northern Colorado local.
>> You're just on a roll tonight, Charles.
>> He's also on the DDA board. He is a
member of the DDA board. He owns this.
He owns a Villagen and he owns a bunch
of other Villagens.
>> Who Okay, what's his name?
>> Ryan Bow, B A U.
So, you can you can get Ryan Bow's
information and me like right off the
DDA website easily.
But, I'll send you his phone number so
you can just pester him.
>> Wait, who gets it?
Oh, cool.
>> Yeah, I think three is a good um
thing to go off of. It sounds like the
barn last year, Miller, it was never
able to contact the owner. So, I think
that's this is a good
um
truncated process for us to go with.
>> And then, the DuBois way will just put
the open application
um
one I guess once we get that up and
going, let us know and we can get that
posted on social media
um so people can hopefully fill that
out. If we don't we get any
applications, I guess just maybe be
thinking
>> The board always has the option in
addition to what the public submits that
we can anybody on the board can also
nominate additional
things, so.
>> Charles, do you want that as soon as
possible?
>> Yes, please.
>> Okay, and then I know that they're still
working on planning for that pump house
tour.
I don't have any new information on
that,
but they're they're going to be doing it
in May. I don't have I don't have a date
on that yet, though.
And then, the mayor's proclamation
um
well,
we can maybe have a a planning meeting
from now and May and see if we can get
that going again unless you've already
>> Cheryl, uh last year we just contacted
the mayor and asked him to pick a date
that was good for him in May, so I can
just do that and let you guys know what
day he'll do that.
>> Okay.
>> And then I imagine we could just use a
similar
proclamation from last year and just
update the dates, basically.
Unless you think there's a better way to
do that.
>> Sometimes the governor does something
too.
>> Yep, yep, he usually does. Um
I'm sure we'll figure out what those
dates are.
Um
Hm?
>> Has the Capitol ever been recognized for
an award just because of its renovation?
Just throwing it out there.
>> Talked in the strategic planning meeting
that it might be a little odd giving an
award to a government building, but I
guess there's nothing that restricts it.
I don't know.
>> Well, that one's different. I said it'd
be weird for the city to give the city
an award, but the city could give a
state award. Okay. And it wouldn't be
quite as weird.
But that is true. I don't think Has it
got the I guess it would be the local
>> I mean it
it received
national awards, but I yeah, not not
from us.
So
>> Is it too late now though? That was like
7 years ago. Yeah.
>> Yeah,
now that we're kind of renovating it
again.
No, I'm just kidding. That's a joke. Um
>> Well, there's a lot more to the Capitol
Square project as well. That was just
that first of
many other elements. There's a whole
plan out there to continue to expand it,
so
the entire conversion's not done yet.
>> Yeah, we we don't think it'll stay the
same, but it's more around the
perimeter.
Several years ago we had kind of asked
about There was a lot of monuments and
statues that were around there that
disappeared and I did see that somebody
is trying to get the Spanish
war thing that was on the
corner the
southeast corner of the capital property
there disappeared and somebody's trying
to get that brought back but
>> Um yeah, that's actually owned by the
museum but it's undergoing conservation
right now. So it's not like in a
basement somewhere. It's actually
getting
>> Well there was
apparently there was a lot of them yeah.
And we had heard there was a lot of them
ended up at the old liquor warehouse or
something and then they were going to
sell the liquor warehouse and
and we like flirted all that stuff go
cuz there was other
things around there that just
disappeared.
>> I was recently in that warehouse and I
only saw two things in there that were
just um just small um granite monuments
that just was like halfway building but
I didn't see any other
statues.
>> Yeah well I just heard that somebody
said that they had been that's where
they ended up and then right after that
there was announcement that the city
that or the state was going to sell that
building and then it's kind of like well
where is that going to end up because
there was a lot of uh
when they tore down some of the houses
that when they created HCI they salvaged
a whole bunch of historic doors and
windows and all kinds of stuff and that
ended up in a warehouse and somebody
said what's all this junk and that all
ended up getting sent to the city dump
and nobody knew about it.
>> Go ahead.
>> Not to like get in the weeds on it but
all of the art in the capital complex is
in the museum's permanent collection. So
even if a warehouse where it's being
stored is sold it still belongs to the
museum and we would need to find
someplace to put it. So, it is all safe.
It's not going anywhere.
Um but, yeah, that's kind of that's how
that process would work. So, it's still
saved in per-
perpetuity. I can never say that word.
Perpetuity.
>> Perpetuity. Thank you, everyone.
>> Um so, yeah, as long as we exist, those
will those will be safe.
>> And the liquor warehouse is not being
sold, cuz it's actually currently being
getting ready to be renovated. So.
Um
Okay, anything else on historic
preservation month?
Okay, marketing and education
of the public.
>> Yes, I think um
I kind of was thinking of a plan and
need to speak with the rest of the
committee members as well, but um
of having kind of a plan to submit to
y'all for each month of like what we're
kind of thinking about doing and being a
little bit strategic of how we're using
social media,
um so that way we're getting the most
engagement.
Um and so, that's kind of what I was
thinking for that. And then but, the
biggest thing to even get started is I
need access
to the Facebook page. I don't remember
who is
>> I I can get you access.
Um
I don't know if we're friends on
Facebook, but I can um I can uh get you
access to it.
>> Yeah, I'll give you my
>> Or at least figure out how to. I have
access to it, so I think I should have
the ability to give it to you.
>> Thank you, Josh. Um and then I was also
wondering, especially for the DuBois
Ward, if that's something we want to
post on social media, um if we were to
spend money on the board's behalf, I
haven't done that yet, uh in order to
create an ad or boost that post to get
out more, um how would we go about that
process? Is that something like I spend
first and ask for reimbursement or how
how does that work?
And are there restrictions on what we
spend money on? I'm sure there are, but
>> Yes.
We've talked about um social media
boosts and stuff before where you can do
targeted ads and targeted views and
stuff like that.
Um
we
under our city purchasing policy
amounts of that level, which is well
under, you know, $3,000. I mean, you're
not going that hard. Those don't require
any
um
special payment must have procurement
stuff. So, it's not something else that
it would be done.
Um the financing for that would come out
of the
the historic preservation account. So, I
think
it'd be most appropriate if the board
would authorize maybe just by a voice
vote like
a monthly limit or something like that
or quarterly engagement limit. Um
preferably like maybe $1,000 most. I
don't know what engagement looks like or
costs. Um but then what it would be done
is just a reimbursement base. You pay,
bring the receipt in. This is easy.
Receipt comes in
and you get reimbursed. Uh
board member Sims does it all the time
um for a lot of the stuff. He he always
gets reimbursed uh for different items
that he has done in the past.
So, the answer is yes and yes.
With permission.
>> Okay. So, maybe that's something when we
bring forward a plan of saying, "Hey, we
want to boost this one. Is everybody
okay with 10 bucks or whatever?"
>> Well, I guess to not prohibit you from
doing anything from now until our next
board meeting, do we want to vote on an
amount right now of I actually don't
know either what any of that costs. So.
>> I would say like 20 bucks max.
>> Okay, but do we want to say 50 at just a
at a
a limit of $50 to go towards marketing
and social media promotion.
Anyone want to make that motion?
>> Chair, I'd like to entertain a motion to
um
allocate
$250
to the
uh
market education and marketing committee
for
uh advertising purposes.
>> That's per year
or month?
>> Uh $250 per quarter for the first
quarter.
I don't know what a
>> Chair, uh may may I just uh suggest um
for we maybe a good motion would be
from now through the second quarter.
Or well, if we're going by fiscal year,
it'd be for the remainder of the third
quarter and the entirety of the fourth.
Or how about this? Just the remainder of
the
>> the remainder of the fiscal year.
Cuz that's that will cover the four
months that are That right? Wow, four
>> I have no idea. What's our fiscal year?
>> July 1st to June 30th. So, the last next
four months or for the remainder of the
fiscal year would probably be the
cleanest.
>> Chair, Chair, I'd like to
restate my motion.
I move that
the board approve $250
to the market marketing and and and um
education committee
for advertising purposes
from now until the end of the the city
fiscal year.
>> I second that.
>> Okay, any comments?
All All in favor say I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
All right.
Motion passes. Okay.
Um
Sorry, where were we? I guess the
marketing and education of the public,
David.
>> Uh nothing new on that.
>> And ornaments, Gary is not here, so none
of us can speak on that. Um
Airport fountain planning, uh
Kelly, um
I guess you want to
discuss the the budget.
>> Yes. Okay. So, um
a couple of updates, I guess, since our
strategic planning meeting, we did
receive a report and a proposal from the
Pacific Coast Conservation Company that
had come up and had discussed and talked
with Patrick a little bit previously,
and then Milward had forwarded
the documentation from Mountain Masonry
that completed the repairs in 2022
to Pacific Coast Conservation so that
they had documentation on what
specifically was used on the fountain.
Um
their assessment essentially
says that because the previous repairs
included an epoxy type coating, which is
non-permeable,
what I'm interpreting is essentially
that's kind of an an inappropriate
treatment because uh any moisture that
does seep into the terracotta block is
not able to evaporate, so that's kind of
exacerbating the issue with moisture
being trapped in there and the bacterial
organic growth that's happening, and it
will continue to bubble and flake off
and deteriorate like into the future.
Um
so there
they they kind of described two
different treatment options.
Um option one, which they said would be
a full coating removal of wherever that
epoxy coating was applied, and then
um
localized stabiliz- stabilization,
excuse me, of the terracotta blocks, and
then filling any of those losses with a
more
compatible repair material and a and a
breathable water repellent coating that
would allow for moisture to evaporate
evaporate in the future. Um So, they did
say this would be kind of a
a longer-term solution, but it's going
to be a much higher cost, and it doesn't
fully eliminate risk of deterioration
moving forward. They said there's a lot
of factors at play, obviously, with the
nature of terracotta and having the
working fountain and running water
through it. It's not going to eliminate
that risk entirely, and it still will
require ongoing maintenance.
Um so, that was their option one. They
didn't actually give us a price for
that, but just as a ballpark after we
followed up and asked, you know, well,
what do you anticipate that would be if
we want to do the longer-term solution
and reduce the maintenance required?
They said for comparison, they're doing
a project in New Mexico right now that's
of similar size, and that one's around
$130,000
for those longer-term repairs, but they
said testing on this would be imperative
to kind of narrow down what's going to
be required to to remove that epoxy
um coating. So, that's option one from
them. Um option two, which is what they
said they recommend in their report,
would be just some smaller targeted
repairs to the areas that are already
kind of compromised and have flaked off
or were damaged in the hail storm, um
which will be a lower initial cost, but
will require more
ongoing annual maintenance um because
that coating will continue to fail over
time. The epoxy that's there that they
don't they wouldn't fully remove
in this option.
Um
cost of that one is around $52,000
for their option two, which is targeted
maintenance and again is going to
require they said probably two to three
days a year where they would come up and
um clean and remove any additional
damaged areas and kind of spot treat
those on an ongoing basis.
So, um sorry, I got a little long-winded
there, but that's kind of a a high-level
overview of their report and the two
options that they proposed.
Um and I do want to point out that with
their option two, that's just the kind
of targeted main- or targeted repairs
and ongoing maintenance, it still does
not include any um pool basin repair or
like improving the waterproofing
of that fountain. So, if we do,
you know, decide we want to keep the
fountain operating,
um it's likely there's going to be
ongoing issues and costs. Um and and
again, that pool basin repair or any
waterproofing improvements, we don't
have a cost for. We have not, you know,
located a contractor that would be able
to address that specifically for the
fountain.
So, with all of that being said, um I
guess as I was trying to think through,
okay, what what are our real options
here and what do we want to recommend?
Um
I would say
the the first option would be if we want
to go for the full longer-term
restoration that's going to be ballpark
$130,000. That cost is to be determined.
Um and try to keep it operating as a
fountain. But if we were to do that, I
think it would
require that we get some sort of written
maintenance agreement with the city. Um
and maybe some allocation of annual
funds to perform that maintenance that
is still going to be required even if
it's done at the higher expense and
you know,
done correctly, quote-unquote, as
Pacific Coast Conservation expressed,
any running fountain is going to require
ongoing maintenance,
um especially with the nature of the
terracotta. So, I don't think we can get
away from that entirely.
Um but that would be one option.
Two would be if we decide we want to pay
to have the fountain restored and
essentially decommission it, um and say
it's not going to be a functioning water
feature anymore, which would
preserve, you know, the historic
structure and the fabric and um
depending on the level of restoration
and the the cost of doing that, whether
we go option one or option two,
any remaining funds from the the will
bequest could potentially then go into
interpretive signage that would not only
tell the history and the story of that,
but also explain like the preservation
of the feature itself and the decision
to decommission it and that, you know,
continuing to run it as a fountain
increases the risk that it just fails in
the future and continues to deteriorate
and we could eventually lose it
entirely.
Um
or
I mean, I guess uh the third option I
would say is if we decide to go with the
lower cost, the 52,000
spot treatment,
um
again, we'd probably need a
a higher ongoing maintenance agreement
with the city
that they're willing to
put however much money that is based on
the the proposal breakdown.
Um
I don't know. They they they said they
could do the initial epoxy removal tests
and mock-ups and come up and do some
work for like a week. That cost alone
came out to like 7,000 some dollars.
So, that's what I'm thinking. I
if we have to do
two to three days of maintenance and
spot treatment every year,
I would think that's probably going to
be a cost of somewhere between five and
ten thousand dollars.
Um
and I don't know how
how we fund that or have that discussion
with the city.
But, I guess what I'm saying there is
with the kind of band-aid I in my mind
it's sort of a band-aid repair if we go
with the lower cost restoration and try
to put more money into beautification
right now. I don't know that that's
responsible long term because yes, we
kind of are able to like check this off
the list and complete a project, but we
do know that the failure is going to
continue and I'm not entirely confident
that it will be properly maintained
moving forward just with, you know, the
history and it
I'm not sure the city has the resources
or the full commitment to
maintain it over just over the past few
years. I think that maybe is part of why
we are where we're at right now.
So,
um I guess one question that
I
wanted to ask after, you know, kind of
going through all of this is if there
were any specific terms in the Wanda
Rice gift um and in that will bequest
that would maybe help inform our
decision about if there's anything
specific that that was for like if if
she wanted to keep the fountain running
and operational or if it's truly just
more to preserve that structure and tell
the story that might help
inform our decision on what what's going
to be best to honor that
that gift and the donors kind of legacy
that they left for the fountain park
whether it's the fountain or airport
fountain park either one.
So I don't know if um
anyone at the city
or if anyone on the board Amber maybe
has access to that will the only thing
that I had or were the terms of the gift
um the only document I have that's
related is
Milward's thank you letter that kind of
said
you know we're excited about this
opportunity and here's some of the
things we envision but doesn't
necessarily
go into detail on if there were the
terms for the gift.
>> Yeah I think Charles is trying to look
it up right now no maybe no just
kidding. Okay. You look busy.
>> That was
a chair I have an idea
of a potential avenue for some
additional funding that can come up
available in November I'm trying to see
if it qualifies it's through the mini
community action grant program.
Um it might require a partnership with
HCI to do that though. Um I'm just
trying to figure out those limitations
but the Wanda Rice um is it
the estate it did have limitations that
it was for the fountain.
Um I don't know if it's that it had to
be running or not but I think there's a
strong
tone in the donation that it was a
running fountain.
It was restoration, but we we do have
that document that we can look up.
>> I guess
thoughts,
comments?
I know that was a lot to take in. Thank
you.
>> yeah, it was just it was a lot of
information and really helpful
information to get um
because my first
comment was that I didn't really fully
realize until right now that it sounds
like a lot of the damage was actually
caused by the first people who restored
the fountain. What did I understand
that?
>> Yes, because that epoxy coating um that
was put on was not brea- it was not
breathable essentially. It it just
caused um
further internal damage to the
terracotta because it trapped the
moisture instead of allowing it to to
breathe.
>> And is there any
>> recourse?
>> Yeah.
>> No.
>> They're just They're straight up just no
options for recourse on that?
>> Yeah. It it's it's been too much time.
It's past its warranty
um
and I we'd have to look at exactly what
what the agreement on that was, but I'm
going to guess that there's probably
it was probably explained of what the
product was to whoever approved it and
we are where we are, I mean.
It's very unfortunate.
>> And to answer your board, yes, we've
looked at the contract for different
ways to see if there's ways to go after
them under warranty and stuff like that
and
that's not It has expired. Um the
warranty time period was
um I know when our planner at the time
it was uh Ms. Stephanie Lowe was the one
who was negotiating with this fountain
this person that it was presented that
this was
the only one who could do this.
And it was a sole source type of
application.
So it No one else had presented
themselves uh through any conferences or
networking or any other communications
of having the ability to do this.
So,
expensive lesson learned.
>> Yeah.
Um and then
just one one other follow-up question to
make sure I understood the the first
more expensive option that would include
um like the pool basin repair, is that
correct? Whereas the second cheaper
option would not include any actual
work on that.
Did I understand that, Kelly?
>> No, neither one of those um
ballpark costs would include pool basin
repair. They essentially said that's
um outside of their scope. They could
oversee that third-party contractor if
needed to do any pool basin or
waterproofing repairs.
Um but no, that's not included in the
their more long-term
full epoxy removal and repair.
>> The There is a um fountain that's almost
identical to ours um in Boulder, and
they theirs is running. So, if we want
to pursue that and find someone that can
do that, I I can always reach out to
uh the city of Boulder and just see what
contractor maintains that cuz I mean,
obviously they have to have some sort of
maintenance to to keep that going. So.
>> Yeah, that pool that fountain looks like
it was probably made by the same people
who made this
I guess.
>> And cheers, is that the one on Pearl
Street Mall in front of the courthouse?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Never seen it before.
>> It's very small.
>> Patrick
>> I don't even know where to start,
but let me start by uh saying Kelly,
thank you to the Kelly and the
committee. This is this is a nice piece
of work that that's been presented to
us.
I don't like either of them.
I mean neither one is is is
satisfactory, I guess, and
in my just my
my initial reaction, and
I mean, we're in a tough spot.
Um
and if Charles is correct,
the
benefactor asked for a running fountain.
We can't afford a running fountain, it
seems like.
I
I really hate to
um
no offense, Charles,
or anyone in the city, depend on the
city, because
I don't think the city has the money
to do this kind of maintenance every
year. We certainly don't.
Um
This is and also the This is the first
time I've heard the term decommission.
And, you know,
given what we're up against, I mean,
that that almost seems like the
you know, like the third option is is we
just decommission it, because we can't
afford it. The city can't afford to to
to maintain this.
Um we're kind of in a really, really
tough tough situation. So, I
I'm disheartened, I guess, and I I I
don't I don't see either option as as
being
>> I will say that that
that 130, right, that was a ballpark,
and I think that if if we want to
explore that option,
I think that Kelly, and you correct me
if I'm wrong, there was a
a 7700, which would they would come and
actually do the proper exploratory work
to really determine, right? They're just
saying 130, because they don't know, and
it's hard to price until they really
like get into it. So, we could move
forward with that $7700
uh assessment, which we would have to do
either way. They had that in the option,
too, anyways. And maybe that's maybe
that's what we do is we kind of say,
"Okay, well, at least come out and tell
us and really let us know what option
one is going to be before we decide
either one." Kelly, is that fair? Am I
>> Correct. Yeah, and it and
yeah, in the email after I had kind of
asked some questions to get a little
clarification, they did come back and
say, cuz I said, "You know, if we go
with the full option one treatment plan,
which is supposed to be more long-term,
do you feel that we could keep the
fountain operating and reduce the risks
of long-term failure?" Um and she
essentially said, "I don't have a great
answer for you. There's so many
factors." Um she talked about adding
some weep holes um toward the bottom of
the fountain that could redirect the
water and help with the spalling.
Um but she said, "Really, the only way
to know is for them to come up and test
and then wait and see what happens." She
said it'd be beneficial to do an initial
testing phase where they come up, they
complete some fills, drill some weep
holes, test different methods for epoxy
removal, and then she said, "Wait a year
to see how things fair."
I'm a little hesitant to to
I don't know, suggest that cuz I feel
like it's a little bit kicking the can
down the road and we're still spending,
you know, seven or eight or 10,000
dollars just to do that and then have
the same
discussion again next year. But, I think
you're correct, Amber. Um
if the board feels like,
you know,
it's in
our best interest and our responsibility
to try to just preserve that fountain
and then whether or not we can say we we
continue operating it or not. Like, I
think
maybe that's what we need to figure out
first.
Is that the number one priority to
preserve the structure, right? Cuz I
don't think it makes sense to put a
bunch of money into beautification of
the park and signage and all of that if
the structure itself continues to fail
and deteriorate moving forward.
Um
but yes, you're correct. Sorry, that's a
long-winded way again of full circle
saying I think that testing costs maybe
we talk to them and just say, "Okay,
we'd like you to come up and do some
tests
and try to narrow it down
what the long-term full removal epoxy
removal and repairs you think would
cost.
>> May- maybe not a full year. Maybe we can
ask if that can be limited, but at least
do our due diligence to really
understand before we go,
you know, yeah, option one, whatever,
we'll spend 130,000 or no, let's just do
option two and maybe option one is
attainable and we just don't know that
yet.
>> Right.
>> Chair, members of the board,
boy, I didn't realize that that Boulder
fountain was almost identical to this
one and I've walked past that like a lot
of times cuz I would just school a
boulder. Um
so, I'm going to send Aaron out a
link in a little bit and she'll email it
to you, but there's a pretty detailed
website on
what's called the Boulder County
Courthouse Fountain, which was renovated
in 1998.
Um it just says it's the fountain was
erected in 1936 by the Boulder Lions
Club. It's smooth terracotta
um
terracotta cladding and strong vertical
lines complement the 1933 Art Deco style
courthouse. The courthouse and fountain
were designed by local architect Glenn
H. Huntington. I don't know if that
rings a bell with us here.
Um
it says um this historical marker's
listed in this topic list of charity and
public work. It's a list for some
historic preservation there. It's
included in Art Deco series list as
well.
It says there's other
um nearby markers that are within 10
miles of that marker, which probably are
also terracotta style, which is
um I'm guessing it's
these other ones. So, if they have more
Oh, no, those are not terracotta. Those
are other ones. But, anyway, this is a
pretty good inventory, which
it was redone in 1998.
I'm
reached out to the Deputy City Manager
of Boulder. He's a classmate of mine
from college.
And we'll see what information we can
get to see if we can
figure out the maintenance, get some
info on that.
>> Great.
>> So, be good.
>> Stephen?
>> Yeah, I was thinking that find out what
Boulder's done cuz if they went through
the same problem and fixed it, then know
who did it and it's holding up since
that's 20 8 years now, 1998 you said.
You know, if theirs has held up for 28
years, then maybe we should find out
what they did
before we spend $130,000 or something.
>> Yeah. Now,
>> so, so, Amber, I guess uh
Do you want
Is is your recommendation to
spend
$7,000 to get an assessment?
>> I Kelly, would you agree with that? I
mean, I I think so. I think that we
start with that step and and do the due
diligence to really understand what's
happening with it. And in in that
process, we can contact cuz they're just
going to take care of the terracotta. We
still got to figure out if we want this
running, how we're going to address the
the pool part of it. Um and maybe
contact with
Boulder, we can figure out who they
used.
>> So,
so, just for clarification, if we spend
7 to 8,000,
we'll get a
will we get terracotta repair and an
assessment or just an assessment?
>> Just an assessment. So, they'll they'll
do some tests and
like Kelly said, they'll
they'll drill what weep holes it I don't
Do you guys know what what we mean by
weep holes?
Um so
usually in like a brick building, if you
look along the bottom, you'll actually
see a little piece of area of mortar
that's open and usually just has a
little
fabric or something over it, but it's
actually allowing the masonry to
breathe. So it's just a hole so air so
moisture can actually get behind there
and dry it out. And so that's what
they're talking about is just adding a
weep hole. And a weep hole can be
various sizes, but just allowing any
moisture that's
>> trapped back there to
to come out.
>> Um and it would be it would be very
minimal. You wouldn't notice it cuz you
probably walk around look at brick
buildings all the time and don't notice
the weep holes, so.
>> I think I'd like to hear from Boulder
first before we say tonight we want to
spend seven or eight thousand dollars.
Yeah, cuz if if they have a different
lead for us
uh I'd like to hear that first and then
vote next month on the
which way to go.
Cuz right now, you know, Boulder may
have come up with a simpler solution or
something that we don't know about, but
cuz uh
like I said, I looked at that fountain
when we were down there and it's kind of
like, you know,
looks pretty much the same construction.
Maybe it was even done by the same
construction company or whatever.
>> Yeah, I guess Pacific Coast, I mean they
they wouldn't be doing anything to the
terracotta as far as repair. They would
just be providing the testing.
And and and putting a couple weep holes
for breathing, so.
>> Yeah, but if Boulder if you know, if we
find out that's what Boulder did, then
we can say, "Yeah, let's go ahead and do
it cuz they were successful." But to
say, "Let's do it, spend the 7,800 and
then come they come back and say, 'Oh,
we tried that and it didn't work and we
did something else.'"
You know, I and I don't know that
another month's going to I'd I'd like to
you know, get to that other
information before I vote on spending
You know, it's
>> But but aren't we going to have to do
the assessment anyway?
I mean, even if Boulder comes up with
this wonderful plan,
it may not be suitable for what we what
our situation is.
Because I
I happen to believe that maybe maybe
this is situational to us because we
have epoxy right now
that we have somehow to deal with which
may or may not be Boulder's situation.
And um
I I
We've been messing around with this
fountain for what? 10 years now?
And and it
It We've got to do something and
assessment seems to make the most sense
right now in terms of
We
Kelly, you feel real confident with this
particular company. They seem pretty
reasonable.
Let's get a our own assessment of our
own fountain to determine where do we go
from here. That's just my opinion. You
know, I
Again, I don't like either option, but
we should we have to know what we're
dealing with and I don't think we have a
clear understanding of that yet.
>> Yeah, um
Yeah, I I sort of agree with with
Patrick. I mean, I think if this is a
recommendation from
um
Yeah, the committee, um I think it's a
good starting point. I don't really love
the second option of just sort of giving
up on it being a functioning fountain. I
think we have this money like um
especially like Kelly was saying there
with that second option, we'd have have
to pay them to come out for two or three
days every year anyway. Um that would
eat into that whatever savings we get
really fast from doing sort of the
the cheaper, um, shorter term
option. I I think we sort of
I feel like we sort of have a
responsibility to try to look into the
long-term solution,
um,
and
if the first step of that is like coming
out, doing the assessment, doing the
testing, and then
they can give us an actual number on
that, then I think that's a good first
step for us to take. So, that's sort of
where I think I come down on it is that
I think
I'm not ready to just like give up on
the fountain and say it's never going to
run water again,
um.
We have the money right now, so, yeah.
>> Yeah, Elizabeth.
Um, yeah, I would agree with, um,
Patrick and Josh as well. Like, we have
we owe it to this donation to see this
through, and to see it through properly,
um, and to say if somebody comes and
talks to us about it of like, these are
the steps we took. We did what was
recommended to us by a professional
company that does this. Um, so, that's
also how I would lean. And I know that
waiting a year for getting back an
assessment is not fantastic, um, but I
do think it'll give us a better look if
we want to go find in-kind donations or
donations in general, or if we want to
look for additional funding or grant
programs or anything like that. It does
give us time in order to do that as well
if the price ends up being more than
what we currently have in our coffers.
>> Um, Chair, I just wanted to let you know
that I looked through some of the
the estate paperwork that we have. It
doesn't indicate anything of how she
wanted it
spent. It just says she has this money
and it needs to be divided up between
these entities and it goes to Airport
Fountain Found or Airport Fountain and
Preservation Project care of the
Cheyenne Historic Preservation Board.
>> Yeah.
Quick question for Cali. Cali, um
is 7,000 7,800 like a like a firm number
that they would
that they've given us for an assessment?
>> Um I was just
Go ahead.
>> So, if we were going to authorize
what is the amount we would have to
authorize as a board?
>> Yeah, um
I don't know that for sure. Looking at
the cost estimate where she broke down
the costs for their proposed option two,
which is just the targeted repairs with
more ongoing maintenance. Um they've got
phase one preparation, which is $1,400
just for administration. I don't know if
that um
full cost would be required up front or
if that could be less if we don't go,
you know, through with the whole $52,000
proposal if that makes sense.
Phase two, they list as epoxy removal
tests and mock-ups of fills and glaze,
and that's $7,745.
So, between the two of those we're at
what? 8,000
45 if my math is correct. So, um
just under $10,000 for those first two
phases.
Um but then what in her email when she
said
we could do an initial testing phase
um wait for a year, see how things fare.
She said we could do an initial
maintenance and include the testing as
part of it.
So, I can get some clarification um, on
what she was suggesting there. If they
do a little bit of maintenance and
repairs, is that similar to this
roughly $9,000 for their phase one and
two or would it vary?
Um, if we're trying to get an approval
tonight to move forward with whatever
that first phase testing um, assessment
looks like.
I'd say maybe $10,000.
>> Not to exceed We could say not to exceed
$10,000.
>> Yeah.
And then I can get you know, the
clarification from Pacific Coast and see
what they think is going to be best
within that
initial amount.
>> Chair, may I make a motion?
>> All right.
>> Uh, I move that the board approve
up to $10,000
for an assessment on uh, the airport
fountain.
Um,
pursuant to um, Kelly's
uh,
conversations with What's the name of
the comp- What's the name of the
company?
>> Pacific Coast.
>> Okay, is there
second?
>> I'd second it.
>> Okay, any discussion?
Nope.
All right. Uh, all in favor
>> I.
>> Say I.
>> Okay.
Uh, any opposed?
All right. Motion passes.
>> Just noting that that's the Boulder
County one that's that's out there. If
you haven't seen it before, so everyone
knows what it's looking like.
>> I I came across this because when we
went to the historic preservation
conference in Boulder, I remember
walking by this.
>> It doesn't have a light on top, but
otherwise it's pretty
>> And it's missing a lot of the
ornamentation, but um
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm. But pretty darn similar.
>> Ours is clean.
>> I I One of the photos I saw, I think it
was uh
a Google said 2014 it was running, so
Um anyways.
Okay.
Um
>> Does that give that committee sort of
direction to move forward? Do you need
Is there more that we should be talking
about at this point? Or does that give
you guys enough like
>> I think that's enough for us to move to
talk to Pacific Coast and we'll we'll
have them give us, you know, they've
given us this proposal that kind of
breaks down a lot of things. We'll
specifically ask for
what we've for for the testing um and
assessment. And that way we can have
that cost um ex- exactly. Um and then
yeah, no, we'll we'll go from there. So
um
>> I'd like to know what how often Boulder
runs theirs. Is it just a part-time
thing or whether they uh
do run it like all summer down there?
You could ask that, Charles.
>> Okay.
Anything else, Kelly? Anything else
before we
move on to the next agenda item?
>> Uh I don't think so right now. Thank
you.
>> Yep.
Okay, pump house.
I don't know if we
Oh, yeah, I was trying to pull up who it
was.
Um
I I guess anything
new since our strategic planning meeting
on the pump house?
>> No, just what
Escobel said that they're actually
working on it, so.
>> Okay.
All right.
>> Anyway, HCI hasn't uh said anything
other than that. I think they're still
planning on that next
uh walk-through thing as all.
>> And the walk-through is sometime the end
of this month?
>> Uh May.
>> Oh, in May. Okay.
>> It's part of the historic preservation
month. That's their little bit.
>> Okay, the next item is design
guidelines. Um
I have not
done anything since our strategic
planning board meeting, but I do think
that um I'll send an email um to you
guys and I I do think we should meet on
that soon. I think the next DDA DDA
board meeting is
next Thursday, and so I'll probably wait
till after that, and then we can get
together and and
uh
discuss that.
Uh
watch list items. I don't know if
there's anything more to
discuss on that right now. Charles, do
you have any reports on
Governor's Mansion District
or or anything like that? Okay.
I guess anyone else want to discuss
watch list items? Okay.
Um new business or
But it shouldn't be old business before
new business?
Sorry. Yes? No? Okay. Old business.
Sorry. The Saving Places Conference. Um
I don't know if we want to kind of talk
about that for a minute. I mean, I know
it was uh
very informative um for me, but I don't
know Patrick and Chuck, Kelly, if you
guys want to
have any comments and
I
Kelly, do you have any any thoughts on
the conference you want to share?
>> Um, I don't know that I have anything
specific, but I did enjoy it. I think it
was a good opportunity with a lot of
good information and I feel like I
learned some things. Um,
I'm still kind of getting my footing on
the board and understanding, you know,
what we do and what we can do, so it was
helpful
to hear from, you know, different
organizations
from communities of varying sizes and
some of the projects that, you know,
well, not necessarily projects, but
things that they've been able to do for
their communities and
yeah.
It was
enjoyable and I appreciate the
opportunity.
>> I think
>> Probably the
three takeaways for me is
um
I got a real strong sense that um
the historic preservation movement is
really struggling with finding
in-kind materials
and finding
uh craftsmen and craftspersons. That
seemed to be a real major theme that
they were trying to promote, that those
two things have made preservation
really, really challenging. The other
thing was I was really impressed with
the AI presentation, artificial
intelligence and how it's used and
misused in uh preservation
and how um
this really for me fascinating concept
about um
phantom input
that AI is only as good as as the input
you put into it. And where you don't
have data, it just makes crap up.
And so, uh in terms of historic
preservation, you have to be real
careful about how you use it, um which
was really a I think for me a
eye-opener.
Um because I think people
as- assign too much um significance to
what you get from from AI-generated
stuff. And it was a cautionary tale for
us as preservationists to be careful
when you go looking and asking AI to
generate information and and how you
have to
uh um David can
kind of uh back me up on this how
they've these guys in California have
used AI AI in in some of their projects
and and really find some really um
significant biases that that um you
know, kind of uh impacted their their
their research. And then the the
probably the the the third thing is that
um you know, I preservation is I I think
going through a real um kind of
um
inflection point in terms of it's not
only buildings anymore, but it's
cultural resources that that is probably
the next frontier of preservation. It's
not only preserving buildings, but how
do you preserve um
older's cultural traditions and and and
cultural resources that are not like
tangible um that seem to be like, you
know, the the the next
frontier
of historic preservation.
And that's going to be a really messy
thing. And and I don't think we'll ever
I I think in not in my lifetime get
there, but
the- there's a lot of people thinking
forward to, you know, it's not only
preserving buildings, but it's how do
you preserve like cultural traditions
that seem to sometimes get lost. And you
know, I living here we see a lot of
you know, the old western
kind of cowboy traditions and culture
things that are sort of starting to slip
and and and how do we preserve those or
are we
you know, supposed to preserve those.
You know, that's a that to me was
something that I thought came through in
in the conference. So
>> Stephen
>> Yeah, the
Like I said, I was interesting. It said
you know, it's good at identifying
like different kinds of buildings, but
it's not good at making
determination of whether something's
contributing or not that you need
somebody to actually
say this is a
Tudor Revival building, but
it's good at narrowing that down if you
want to do a whole bunch of buildings
to get that identification cuz there's a
lot of those things that I don't know
the difference and sometimes you get a
building that's got three different
features styles of construction, but uh
and one other they they were pushing
linseed oil paint for windows.
Basically, you have to take it down to
the wood and then paint it on there. He
said it's uh I was wondering about if
you had a wood house it's basically not
economical because you have to take it
down to bare wood. And so if it's you
know, if you
So it would help on windows cuz it you
only have to paint he said it about 7 to
14 years is about it has about double
the life of what what he calls plastic
paint, which is what we call latex.
And but there are
place out of I think it was Maine that
is bringing the stuff over from England,
but they're
if there's a increase in demand, you
know, they could probably start
manufacturing it
here in the United States and one thing
I don't know where to bring it up but uh
the uh University of Colorado Denver
branch where they have a program for
historic preservation but they said I
see that you're doing another historic
preservation uh conference in Cheyenne
this summer.
And I was like, "Oh, I hadn't I hadn't
heard of it." Apparently, Shippo sent
out sent them a request for papers. So,
that was the first I had heard of it.
It's like the one they did in Laramie 2
years ago but it's going to be in
Cheyenne.
>> I think it's going to be in Casper.
>> Oh, but they said it was Cheyenne but I
don't I don't know what it
>> There's There's two different things.
There's Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> There's the um There's going to be the
one in Casper that you're talking about
but then Shippo is putting together a
cultural heritage institute. It's not
historic preservation. It's cultural
heritage. So, it's I think it's a lot
more like archive than like physical
paper for them.
>> What is that?
>> It's like a separate
>> Okay.
>> And chair, does that wrap up board
member discussion on the conference?
>> Uh well, Chuck, did you want to
Oh, Kelly commented on the I Did you
want to
say anything about it?
>> my comments brief.
Um
three-day conference. I stayed in town
Friday night for
I had travel plans the next morning. So,
I was there till Friday at
4:00 p.m. So, I took a lot of notes,
learned a lot of things.
You have to pivot when you go to this um
type of conference. You You're You go to
a state-specific
um seminars like state historical fund
grants 101 but that's for Colorado, not
necessarily for Wyoming but you go to
learn so you keep an open mind. Then you
pivot to um They had redevelopment
projects on Main Street.
And then I went to a federal type um
seminar session about section 106 and
HPA.
And they talked about that four-part
process. That was very enlightening. If
you're new to a to a board like I am,
you you know, you keep an open mind, you
learn as much as you can, take good
notes.
And um I don't know about this horse
barn. I don't know where the horse barn
is in Cheyenne, but I did go to a
session on barns rehabilitation and
reuse strategies on barns. That was
good. And then yeah, I pivoted again.
They had a whole session on uh
re-centering indigenous perspectives.
It was called We Are the Land. So, that
was very worthwhile getting indigenous
perspectives.
And uh you know, they're taking
proposals for next year, 2027.
Um but it's very Colorado-centric. So,
you come in from Wyoming and they're
They're They're
They're curious. They're friendly. They
want to know why you're there. How long
it take you to drive down? Um
So, you you know, you play nice. And um
So, it was very worthwhile
uh for me as a new person.
>> Yeah, I sat with the mayor of Idaho
Springs, population 2,100. He goes,
"Yeah, we give our historic preservation
board $60,000 a year."
>> Be nice.
>> So, but they do run the museum down
there with the they vault their people
volunteer, but it's apparently that does
pay for some of the electricity or
something.
>> Um
>> Surprise we get 130,000.
>> Um while I'm Googling some information
real quick. Hold on.
Just seeing what their general fund
budget is there. Uh General fund budget
in Idaho Springs
looks like it's 64 million
772,000
dollars.
Which our general fund budget for our
town is a little bit bigger, 74 million
dollars.
>> A little bit bigger.
>> So just saying that Beau Jo's Pizza does
a lot of that contribution, I'm sure.
And the dispensaries probably help out
just as much there.
To propel both of those upwards.
>> higher property taxes, don't they?
>> And the property tax a little bit
higher. Um Morgan, you were a staff
attendee, do you want to come and give
your perspective on what you learned at
the conference? I know you ended up sick
later, so
why don't you come on down?
In the section 106 that you're talking
about, um
who was here last time we actually went
through that process? Who was on the
board? Cuz we've gone through the
process more recently.
Does anyone recall that?
Wow, have we switched over? I think
Josh, were you here at the tail end of
that? And David, maybe?
>> Well, every every once in a while we'll
get, you know, somebody like when they
were doing when WYDOT was doing their
roads by the fountain and they'll ask us
about it or they're putting up a radio
tower and ask us if we have any concerns
about adverse effects on historic
resources.
>> Yeah.
>> And
usually we just say, "Yeah, we'd like to
be included in the conversation." and
then don't really hear anything.
>> Yeah, if the FCC came in, if someone
came up that application to add a
antenna right at the top of the depot,
which I'd hope it never go that far,
they would want a section 106 review.
The Purgatory Bridge, the Lincoln
Highway that was removed, they had a
review.
And that one resulted in, um
unfortunately, just an upgraded marker,
like at Carey and and Lincoln Way, but
that's what happened there. So, any
perspectives to share?
>> Um, I mean, it was fun, um, interesting
to learn the Colorado perspective. I've
learned the Oklahoma and Kentucky one.
So, it was nice to add this. Um, it's
pretty cool to see the other projects,
seeing how that's
going on. It was nice to talk to other
planners and how they do it in their
cities. So, yeah.
>> Okay. Um, strategic planning meeting.
Um, I think that was pretty successful.
Um, I I don't know if we want to if
anyone wants to just kind of discuss
anything specific there, but it looks
like that the planning goals was updated
and sent out to everyone. So,
if anyone has any corrections or
anything to that.
>> It wasn't sent out to me, but um,
>> Is it the agenda?
>> Oh, okay. I just didn't see it. But, do
we need to do like approve that or
anything?
>> Yes.
Um,
so yes, if someone wants to make a
motion to approve the strategic planning
goals that we
>> I'll move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Any
comments?
All right. All in favor say I.
>> I.
All right.
Motion passes.
Okay. Um, and the 2025 annual report, we
just signed that, so
thanks to Josh and and Aaron. We got
that all nailed out last week, so that's
should be
posted, I don't know, uh, shortly.
>> Yeah, we'll, um, get the mayor to sign
it, and then we do need two signatures,
one from Kelly and one from Patrick
Vaughn. So, I'll email them, and they
can sign those.
Um, and then we will get it sent to Ship
out.
And published.
>> Yay.
>> Now we know that process.
Um, big boy sign.
Um, the parks and rec department had
taken it out because the sign was
damaged and so
they to protect the plaque that was in
there,
um, they took it down but
Patrick Bustos indicated today it is
back up.
>> Yes, it is.
And I even had a nice chat with the
parks person that was working on it.
He was out there this morning.
>> Awesome.
Uh, other business attendance contact
numbers who have been absent. It sounds
like, uh, do you want to share this
news? Okay.
>> Yeah, sure. Through you. Um,
Don has given his resignation. Um, so he
is no longer on the board. And the
mayor's office has
um, noticed publicly that we are looking
for new members. And so those
applications are open now.
>> Yeah, I saw that ad that like it's an
announcement not an ad in the paper
couple days ago. So, for two positions.
>> And just a quick question. Are are those
to fill out a term or full terms
Charles? How does that work?
>> Uh, the the biggest the one for Don will
be to fill the unexpired term and the
other one would be a new term.
Um, I would like to note that I believe
in the bylaws it says that you all are
able to recommend somebody to join the
board. So, if you all know someone who
you would like to have join the board
collectively,
um, I don't know if there's a name that
rings
right now that you'd like to talk about.
Um, what we would ask is that you ask
them to complete the nomination form um,
online.
And then we'll relay that information to
the mayor. Likewise, if you as
individuals have that
you're welcome to contact Aaron.
Contact Aaron.
Or Morgan to
identify someone that you would feel is
interested. I don't know when the
selection's going to occur, but what we
can do is
make sure that we discuss some of the
candidates here.
Additionally, if you wanted to just to
have a
grouping of three or so or three or four
members to review applications
as like a subcommittee type of role
I wouldn't have any issue with that. I
think that would be fair and and good.
>> Yeah. I
Don didn't mention when I talked to him,
but does he get a brick or something
sent for his years that he was on the
board or
>> He'll get a brick camera. No, um
Don has been a pleasure to work with on
the board by the way over the all the
years I've been here Don's been here. I
remember one of the first times I met
Don, we went and did a photo inventory
of the Coal Shopping Center, went into
buildings into the old Blockbuster paid
my fines, paid his fines, it was all
good. The old Prairie Restaurant over
there we we did that.
And I've always seen that Don's been one
who loves to take photos. He does great
photos. He's always jumped up and down
to do those. In the correspondence we
had regarding his resignation, I did say
this isn't going to stop me from
reaching out to you to take photos, so
be prepared for future volunteer efforts
for preservation and documentation. He
said he'd be thrilled.
>> Great.
Um and I guess
Patrick Bond, I don't know if we have a
an update and if he plans on
attending any more. I have not
personally spoken to him. I just had
information from Millward that he was
going
to miss this meeting. So, I don't Does
anyone else
Charles anyone?
Okay.
Um well, I
I'll reach out to him and we can just
kind of see where he he stands. Um
And just see if he's needing to take a
leave of absence. And I Do we have to
We don't need to like
vote on that or whatever. Is there
something in in our
that allows board members to take
a leave of absence?
>> Just excuse that as
>> Okay. Okay. I Cool cuz I think it says
that if you miss X amount of meetings,
you're not
>> Well,
if they're
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah, unexcused meetings that he's got
health on, but
>> Okay. I got it.
>> The failure to take action to remove is
is
is excuse. Plus, you noted excusal.
>> Got it.
>> needed.
>> Okay.
Um
I guess any Oh, go ahead.
>> I I had just one follow-up question
about the Louisa Swain building. Is
there any movement on that or do you
need anything from the board in terms of
like that the conversation we had last
meeting?
>> Um Chair, do you know? Not at this time.
We gave the
template that Sheridan gave us for the
covenants. We gave that to um
the federal government, the contact that
I have there. And they were take going
to take it and
go through it with their attorneys to
see what they want to change. And then
they were going to send it over to us.
And the city's attorneys would look
through it, but we haven't heard back
from them yet. So, they must be
reviewing it.
Yeah.
>> One thing, um
I was driving by Lions Park and they've
taken down the Frontier Park Indian
Village. Did we do a
uh
What is it called? Uh uh
>> Photographs?
>> Photographs of that before it was gone?
>> I I did on behalf of the board. I went
over and it was probably like a May or
June or or no, I guess it would have
been after CFD, so August.
Um and I took a bunch of pictures and
it's on the shared drive that they set
up for us. So, I I have probably 100
pictures in there for whatever.
>> Thank you.
>> And I believe that the when we talked
about the CFD about the shoot, they did
a massive inventory of that on their
own. I don't know if
Um I wonder if we can get some
information on that.
>> By the time I asked them, they'd already
turned it down. It was down.
I don't know about their own inventory.
>> New business?
Anyone have any new business?
No? All right. You ready to adjourn?
Okay.
Thanks.
Wait.
All right.
I just wanted to do